<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on N D BHARATH</title>
    <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on N D BHARATH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:32:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>June 30th</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/ninth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:32:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/ninth/</guid>
      <description>installed aws cli. Created key pair using aws cli.  aws ec2 create-key-pair --key-name MyKeyPair --query &#39;KeyMaterial&#39; --output text &amp;gt; MyKeyPair.pem Check to see if ketpair is created.
aws ec2 describe-key-pairs --key-name To delete key pair
aws ec2 delete-key-pair --key-name MyKeyPair Creating instance with EC2 aws ec2 run-instances &amp;ndash;image-id ami-0c1a7f89451184c8b &amp;ndash;count 1 &amp;ndash;instance-type t2.micro &amp;ndash;key-name MyKeyPair &amp;ndash;security-group-ids sg-903004f8 &amp;ndash;subnet-id subnet-6e7f829e
 A tag is a label that you assign to an AWS resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 29th</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/eight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:32:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/eight/</guid>
      <description>Created new directory awsinterraform and added main.tf file added the following in the file. Credentials are hard coded for now.  provider &amp;quot;aws&amp;quot;{ region = &amp;quot;ap-south-1&amp;quot; access_key = &amp;quot;xxx&amp;quot; secret_key = &amp;quot;xxx&amp;quot; } resource &amp;quot;aws_instance&amp;quot; &amp;quot;my_second_server&amp;quot; { ami = &amp;quot;ami-0c1a7f89451184c8b&amp;quot; instance_type = &amp;quot;t2.micro&amp;quot; }  This is an ubuntu server with instance type t2.micro    Installed aws cli and added security credentials.  terraform { required_providers { aws = { source = &amp;quot;hashicorp/aws&amp;quot; version = &amp;quot;~&amp;gt; 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 22nd</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:32:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</guid>
      <description>Installed Terraform on linux terminal, following steps given by this doc.   
  Created new directory and created a new file main.tf with the terraform configuration.
  terraform init command allows Terraform to interact with Docker.
  terraform plan does a dry run of your configuration.
  terraform apply deploys changes according to main.tf.   
  Created an AWS educate account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 19th</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 11:29:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/docker/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER
Docker is an easy way to package an application with all its configuration and dependancies. Before Docker the developers and operations would have to manually downoad dependencies and often it would be the case that due to communication errors there might be problems. The public repository that stores images for Docker is Dockerhub. -Only one command that is docker pull/ docker run is required to pull the package along with the configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My fourth post</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/fifth_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/fifth_post/</guid>
      <description> Build site with github actions using a default template. Added project to circle ci. First bulid failed due to non existance of config.yml file. Added config.yml to required location with necessary content. Result: Build failed. Watched tutorials to understand CI/ CD properly.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Third Post</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/fourth_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/fourth_post/</guid>
      <description>Test sites with various themes. 
  Tested how to add content and how changing various files would affect the site. 
  -Ran site successfully</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Second Post</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/second_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/second_post/</guid>
      <description>Shifted from using vm on linux to dual boot linux.
  Downloaded hombrew as a package installer.
  Used homebrew to install hugo and asciinema.
  Created a new hugo site and made a local repository. 

  Used visual studio code for more comfortable interface.
  Authenticated github site with ssh key for more secure authentication.
  Used git init to make git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description> Learnt the basics of Git and Github. I learnt how to write in markdown. Experimented with hosting HTML on github.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technologies</title>
      <link>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/third_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndbharath.github.io/posts/third_post/</guid>
      <description>TECHNOLOGIES LEARNT
Hugo: Hugo is a static site generator. Unlike dynamic sites where the page is build dynamically when a visitor visits, hugo builds pages when you create or update it. Hugo is used commonly to build sites or company sites.
asciinema: Records terminal output on command asciinema rec.
Git: It is a version control system used to track changes in the source code. Git repository is the place where the snapshots are saved by commiting after sending to staging area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
